Guide to the Czesław Miłosz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Others, 1928-1998; Series VIII; 7.51; (19 boxes)
  - Writings about Miłosz
    - Thackery, Joseph, "Czeslaw Milosz -- The uses of a philosophy of poetry," typescript (copy), 1981 (Box 192, Folder 2978)
    - Trznadel, Jacek, "Czym ja jestem i czym oni sa" (Polish original and French translation), typescript (copies), 1980 (Box 192, Folder 2979)
    - Walicki, Andrzej, "Spotkania z Miłoszem", typescript (copy), undated (Box 192, Folder 2980-2981)
    - Witkowski, Tadeusz, "I tyłko w zaprzeczeniu dom swój miała swiętość?," typescript carbon, undated (Box 192, Folder 2982)
    - Wojewoda, Grażyna, "Czesław Miłosz: Dolina Issy ," typescript carbon, 1984 (Box 192, Folder 2983)
    - Zaleski, Marek
      - "O Poezji Traktatowej Czesława Miłosza: Poezja jako wyraz samoswiadomosci kultury," typescript, 1976 (Box 193, Folder 2984)
      - Utworów poetyckie (review), typescript carbon, 1978 (Box 193, Folder 2985)
    - Zaręba, Zofia, "Dwa nurty czyli międzywojenna poezja Czesława Miłosza ..." (MA thesis), typescript carbon, 1981 (Box 193, Folder 2986)
    - Zubelewicz, Jan, "O 'Obowiazku' Miłosza," typescript, 1985 (Box 193, Folder 2987)
    - Various authors, Poems dedicated to Miłosz, holograph and typescript, 1950-1982, undated (Box 193, Folder 2988)
      Authors include Stanisław Byszewski, Edwin Drummond, Zbigniew Herbert, and Richard Lourie.
    - Unidentified, 1998, undated (Box 193, Folder 2989-2996)
  - General Writings of Others
    - Albinski, W., poems in Polish, typescript (copy), 1977 (Box 194, Folder 2997)
    - Amstisławski, Jan, "Anti-Herling," typescript, undated (Box 194, Folder 2998)
    - Andruszkiewicz, Franciszek, poems in Polish, typescript, 1928-1947 (Box 194, Folder 2999-3002)
      Includes a letter from Andruszkiewicz to Miłosz.
    - Argent, Pierre d', Poèmes de ma chambre et du matin, typescript, 1989 (Box 194, Folder 3003)
      Includes a letter from d'Argent to Miłosz.
    - Avens, _____, prose in English, typescript (copy), undated (Box 194, Folder 3004)
    - Balcewiczowa, Zofia (née Jeleńska), "Rodowód Zofii z Jeleńskich-Balcewiczowej," typescript carbon, corrected, 1988 (Box 194, Folder 3005)
    - Barańczak, Stanisław
      Includes letters from Barańczak to Miłosz.
      - Widokówka z tego świata, typescript, 1988 (Box 194, Folder 3006)
      - Tablica z Macondo, printout, 1989 (Box 194, Folder 3007)
      - Jak wam się podoba (Polish translation by Barańczak), printout, 1989 (Box 194, Folder 3008)
    - Baterowicz, Marek, Łamiąc gałęzie ciszy, typescript, 1980 (Box 195, Folder 3009)
    - Bereś, Stanisław, "Już nic, to tylko stoi obłok nad sekcja ....," typescript carbon, undated (Box 195, Folder 3010)
    - Bielobradek, Joanna, poems, typescript, 1990 (Box 195, Folder 3011)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, poems translated from Russian to Polish by Stanisław Barańczak, draft, typescript (copy), 1987 (Box 195, Folder 3012-3013)
      Includes a letter from Barańczak to Miłosz.
    - Brodsky, Joseph and Gregory Freidin, two occasional poems, typescript, 1996 (Box 195, Folder 3014)
    - Bryant, Donald, "On Angels" (musical score), 1981 (Box 195, Folder 3015)
    - Bujała, Bogusław, poems in Polish, typescript, 1992 (Box 195, Folder 3016)
    - Byrski, Tadeusz and Irena, "Projekt organizacji teatru terenowego ze studiem teatralnym," typescript carbon, 1957 (Box 195, Folder 3017)
    - Cichowicz, Stanisław, poems, typescript, 1990 (Box 195, Folder 3018)
    - Codrescu, Andrei, The disappearance of the outside, draft, typescript, 1989 (Box 195, Folder 3019-3021)
      Includes a letter from Addison-Wesley Publishing Company to Miłosz.
    - Czyżewski, Krzysztof, Modlitwa serca, draft, typescript, circa 1989 (Box 195, Folder 3022)
    - Dobrowolski, Jacek, poems in Polish and English, undated (Box 195, Folder 3023)
    - Dybciak, Krzysztof, "Świety byt nasz i dzień," typescript carbon, undated (Box 195, Folder 3024)
    - Dzień, Mirosław, poems in Polish, typescript, 1991 (Box 195, Folder 3025)
    - Erigena, John Scotus, "Homily on the Prologue to the Gospel of St. John", English translation by Christopher Bamford, typescript, 1980 (Box 195, Folder 3026)
    - Eskowitz, Leonard, poems in English, typescript, 1989 (Box 196, Folder 3027)
    - Evseev, Boris, Zven'ia, typescript (copy), 1991 (Box 196, Folder 3028)
    - Gieysztor, Gina, Polish translations of Anna Akhmatova, typescript, undated (Box 196, Folder 3029)
    - Gimbutas, Marija, Bibliography, typescript, 1960s (Box 196, Folder 3030)
    - Ginsberg, Allen (compiler), Photographic Poets: An Anthology, typescript (copy), 1991 (Box 196, Folder 3031)
      Includes a letter from Ginsberg to Miłosz.
    - Gorczynska, Renata (translator), English translations of poems by Aleksander Wat, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 196, Folder 3032)
    - [Gorska, Halina?], memoir on Vilnius, typescript, 1980 (Box 196, Folder 3033)
    - Górski, Ryszard, poems in Polish, typescript and holograph, 1989 (Box 196, Folder 3034)
    - Gregg, Linda, poems in English, typescript, undated (Box 196, Folder 3035)
    - Grodska-Antoszkiewicz, Irmina, Miłosierdzie Pana Wezwania, typescript, 1989 (Box 196, Folder 3036)
    - Grosjean, Ok-koo, poem in English, undated (Box 196, Folder 3037)
    - Grossbardt, Andrew, poem in English, typescript, undated (Box 196, Folder 3038)
    - Gruszka-Zych, Barbara, poems in Polish, typescript, 1994 (Box 196, Folder 3039)
    - Guze, Zygmunt, "Pamiętnik (Memoir)", draft, holograph, corrected, 1961-1963 (Box 196, Folder 3040-3042)
      Includes a letter from Guze to Miłosz.
    - Harris, Peter, poems, typescript, 1981 (Box 197, Folder 3043)
    - Henry, Edgar, Madonna darkness, typescript (copy), undated (Box 197, Folder 3044)
    - Herbert, Zbigniew, Report from a besieged city, English translation by John and Bogdana Carpenter, typescript (copy), circa 1985 (Box 197, Folder 3045)
    - Herling-Grudzinski, Gustaw, "Cultural commentary no. 322", 1963 (Box 197, Folder 3046)
    - Hesse, Erik, Music, typescript, 1989 (Box 197, Folder 3047)
    - Idezak, Henryk, poems in Polish, holograph, 1989 (Box 197, Folder 3048)
    - Illg, Jerzy (editor), Kundera, typescript carbon (and copies), 1987 (Box 197, Folder 3049-3057)
    - Iribarne, Louis, English translation of by Operetta by Witold Gomrowicz, typescript carbon, 1970 (Box 198, Folder 3058)
    - Ivask, Ivar, poems in translation by unidentified translators, typescript, 1986, undated (Box 198, Folder 3059-3060)
    - Jałowiecki, Mieczysław, Z lat minionych (memoirs, volumes 2 and 3), typescript (copy), 1988 (Box 198, Folder 3061-3064)
      Includes a letter from Krystyna Laskowicz to Miłosz.
    - Jankowska, Bożenna, poems in Polish, printout, 1995 (Box 198, Folder 3065)
    - Kane, Robert Hilary, "Through the moral maze," printout (copy), undated (Box 198, Folder 3066)
    - Kasjanowicz, Eugeniusz, poems in Polish, typescript, 1995 (Box 198, Folder 3067-3068)
    - Kastmiler, Peter (translator), Contemporary Yugoslav poetry, typescript (copy), 1981 (Box 198, Folder 3069)
    - Kelertas, Violeta (editor), "Come into my time": Contemporary Lithuania in prose fiction, printout, 1991 (Box 198, Folder 3070)
    - Kernje, Anna, poems, holograph (copy), 1998 (Box 199, Folder 3071)
    - Knapp, Liza, dissertation abstract, typescript (copy), undated (Box 199, Folder 3072)
    - Koehler, Krzysztof, poems, typescript, 1986 (Box 199, Folder 3073)
    - Kolecki, Wojciech, Untitled work on Stanisław Brzozowski in French, typescript (copy), 1988 (Box 199, Folder 3074)
    - Kołakowski, Leszek, "Komentarz do Nawróconego ," typescript (copy), corrected, 1997 (Box 199, Folder 3075)
    - Korzeniewski, Bohdan, Noc (novella), typescript, corrected, 1996 (Box 199, Folder 3076)
    - Kownacki, Stanisław, Letter to the editors of Myśl Polska on Wiktor Trościanko's article "Obóz Laureata," typescript (copy) and holograph, 1982 (Box 199, Folder 3077)
    - Kozioł, Urszula, poems in English, typescript, 1988 (Box 199, Folder 3078-3079)
    - Kuharski, Allen, essays on Witold Gombrowicz, typescript (copies), 1989 (Box 199, Folder 3080-3082)
    - Lange, Oscar, "Statement to the world Jewish Congress by Prof. Oscar Lange ...," typescript carbon, 1946 (Box 199, Folder 3083)
    - Lawson, Jon Arno, poems, printout, 1998 (Box 199, Folder 3084)
    - Levine, Madeline (translator), "Polish culture after communism," by Teresa Walas, printout, 1996 (Box 199, Folder 3085)
    - Lewandowski, Józef, "Rosja między zachodem a wschodem w opinii Kluczewskiego i Milukowa," printout, 1992 (Box 199, Folder 3086)
    - Lisiecka, Alicja, "Para rękawiczek," typescript (copy), 1985 (Box 200, Folder 3087)
    - Lizakowski, Adam, poems in Polish, typescript and printed versions, 1987 (Box 200, Folder 3088)
    - Lord, John, "Ode to Naropa," typescript (copy), 1988 (Box 200, Folder 3089)
    - Lourie, Richard, The Slugabed's matins, typescript, undated (Box 200, Folder 3090)
    - Lourie, Richard and Tadeusz Mason (translators), English translations of Polish poetry, typescripts (copies), some corrected by Miłosz, undated (Box 200, Folder 3091)
    - Ławrynenko, Jurij, prose in Polish, circa 1958 (Box 200, Folder 3092)
    - Mahoney, Peter, poems in English, 1991 (Box 200, Folder 3093)
    - Maksimowska, Jadwiga, poems in Polish, 1991 (Box 200, Folder 3094)
    - Mally, Casimir, Jaselka polonijne, typescript (copy), 1980 (Box 200, Folder 3095)
    - Martz, Erin, By Grace (chapbook), typescript (copy), 1990 (Box 200, Folder 3096)
    - Matejko, Marek, poems in Polish, typescript, 1980s (Box 200, Folder 3097)
    - Matus, Thomas, English translation of The Life of the Five Brothers of Ravenna, by Saint Bruno, of Querfurt, typescript (copy), 1989 (Box 200, Folder 3098-3100)
      Alternate title: The Mystery of Master Romuald
    - McCabe, James, The white battlefield of silence, printout (copy), 1998 (Box 201, Folder 3101)
    - Merrill, Charles, "The journey or The massacre of the innocents," typescript (copy), 1995 (Box 201, Folder 3102)
    - Miller, C. David, "Christianity in the space age: Oscar Milosz's poetics of reality," typescript, 1986 (Box 201, Folder 3103)
    - Milosz, Oscar V. de Lubicz
      - Poems, English translation by Roma Huk, typescript (copy), 1985 (Box 201, Folder 3104)
      - La Clef de l'Apocalypse, typescript, undated (Box 201, Folder 3105)
    - Mintal, Wojtek, 4th grade exercise-book in Polish literature, 1981 (Box 201, Folder 3106)
    - Mlynarski, Jan-Kajetan, poems in Polish, handwritten, 1992 (Box 201, Folder 3107)
    - Mrożek, Sławomir, Portret, typescript carbon, 1987 (Box 201, Folder 3108)
    - Muszer, Dariusz, Ludziojad, printout, 1991 (Box 201, Folder 3109)
    - Mutz, Stanisław, prose in Polish, printout, undated (Box 201, Folder 3110)
    - Myers, Margaret, poems in English, typescript, undated (Box 201, Folder 3111)
    - Napiórkowski, Jacek, Lodowiec, chapbook, 1990 (Box 201, Folder 3112)
      Includes a letter from Ryszard Brykojlo.
    - Nathan, Leonard, poems in English, typescript, 1992 (Box 201, Folder 3113)
    - Niecko, Jacek, "Epigram," printout, undated (Box 201, Folder 3114)
    - Niemierowska, Renata Maria, "nic się nie dzieje w czasie," chapbook, 1990 (Box 201, Folder 3115)
    - Nowicki, Peter, The Temple of Delilah, typescript, undated (Box 201, Folder 3116)
    - Ogrodowczyk, Andrzej, Jabłuszko ziemi, typescript (copy), undated (Box 201, Folder 3117)
    - Pellauer, David (translator), "Evil, a challenge to philosophy and theology," by Paul Ricoeur, typescript (copy), undated (Box 201, Folder 3118)
    - Piekarski, Thomas, Winchester Mystery House, typescript, 1989 (Box 201, Folder 3119)
    - Piel, François (translator), poems, typescript (copy), undated (Box 201, Folder 3120)
    - Pinsky, Robert, "Control, Freedom, and the Appetite for Poetry," typescript, undated (Box 201, Folder 3121)
    - Puć, Arkady, poems in Polish, typescript, undated (Box 201, Folder 3122)
    - Quinn, Arthur, "The riddles of Samson," typescript, undated (Box 201, Folder 3123)
    - Rapnicki, Marek, poems in Polish, typescript, 1987 (Box 202, Folder 3124)
    - Reicher, Aniela, "Współczesni Mohikanie," typescript, 1980 (Box 202, Folder 3125)
    - Retucha, Ryszard, "Dostojewski zawsze," typescript (copy), 1992 (Box 202, Folder 3126)
    - Rosiek, Stanislaw (translator), Malarz życia nowoczesnego by Charles Baudelaire, printout, 1998 (Box 202, Folder 3127)
    - Rusiecki, Jacek, poems in Polish, handwritten and typescript (copy), 1990 (Box 202, Folder 3128)
    - Rysakowski, Waldemar, poems in Polish, typescript, 1989 (Box 202, Folder 3129)
    - Salamon, Joanna, "Wobec portretu Gombrowicza," typescript (copy), 1988 (Box 202, Folder 3130)
    - Saloni, Stanisława, poems, printout, 1992 (Box 202, Folder 3131)
    - Schiller, Anna, Stanisława, printout, 1999 (Box 202, Folder 3132)
    - Schwartz, Leonard, poems in English, typescript (copy), 1986 (Box 202, Folder 3133)
    - Senajko, Krzysztof, poems in Polish, typescript, circa 1985 (Box 202, Folder 3134)
    - Shaw, Alan, poems in English, typescript (copy), undated (Box 202, Folder 3135)
    - Siekierski, Maciej, "Landed Wealth in the Grand Duchy of Lithuania," (dissertation), typescript, 1984 (Box 202, Folder 3136-3138)
    - Siemaszko, Zdzisław A., Henryk Dembiński: dzieciństwo i wczesna młodość, typescript, 1987 (Box 202, Folder 3139)
    - Słonimski, Antoni, "Odprawa," typescript, 1950s (Box 202, Folder 3140)
    - Sojka, Herbert, poems in Polish, typescript carbon, 1988 (Box 202, Folder 3141)
    - Smith, Huston, review of Encountering God: A spiritual journey from Bozeman to Banaras by Diana L. Eck, typescript, 1994 (Box 203, Folder 3142)
    - Sobczyk, Władysław (editor), Śpiewana i mówiona (folk songs and rhymes), typescript, 1986 (Box 203, Folder 3143-3147)
    - Sruoginis, Laima (translator), poems by Marcelijus Martinaitis, printout, 1990 (Box 203, Folder 3148)
    - Statkevičius, Algirdas, "The most enigmatic mystery of mankind," typescript (copy), 1989 (Box 204, Folder 3149)
    - Stewart, Dann, poems in English, printout, undatd (Box 204, Folder 3150)
    - Stokowski, Marek, poems in Polish, tyepscript, 1988 (Box 204, Folder 3151)
    - Stolarska, Barbara, review of Baśni i legendy litewskie by Oscar Milosz, typescript, 1987 (Box 204, Folder 3152)
    - Strumiłło-Miłosz, Grażyna, Znad Świtezi w głab tajgi: Rozmowy z moją matką, typescript, undated (Box 204, Folder 3153)
    - Sulik, B., screenplay in English, typescript (copy), 1988 (Box 204, Folder 3154)
    - Swianiewicz, S. "The University of Wilno in historical perspective," typescript (copy), 1979 (Box 204, Folder 3155)
    - Szymik, Jerzy, poems in Polish, typescript and printed version, 1988 (Box 204, Folder 3156)
    - Taufer, Veno (author and translator) and Milne Holton (translator), Water People, typescript, copy, 1988 (Box 204, Folder 3157-3158)
      Includes a letter from Taufer to Miłosz.
    - Tropp Gubler, Janina, poems in Polish, typescript, 1963-1979 (Box 204, Folder 3159)
      Includes a letter from Witold Gubler to Miłosz.
    - Tuwim, Julian, "Ball at the Opera," English translation by Madeline and Steven Levine, typescript (copy), 1982 (Box 204, Folder 3160)
    - Urbanowicz, Bohdan Tadeusz, Ścieżki i spotkania, typescript (copy), 1988 (Box 204, Folder 3161)
      Includes photographs of sculptures.
    - Venclova, Tomas, Aleksander Wat: Life And Art of an Iconoclast, proposal and sample chapter, 1992 (Box 204, Folder 3162)
    - Vincenz, Stanisław, "Leśny żyd," typescript, undated (Box 204, Folder 3163)
    - Wakliss, Sandra, English translations of Polish poetry by various authors, typescript (copy), 1979 (Box 204, Folder 3164)
    - Warsza, Adam (collector), "Wspomnienia," typescript (copy), 1970 (Box 205, Folder 3165)
      Includes a letter from Warsha to Miłosz.
    - Weil, Simone, excerpts from diary, copies and "La Porte" (poem), typescript, 1959 (Box 205, Folder 3166)
    - Wenderoth, Joe, poems in English, typescript, undated (Box 205, Folder 3167)
    - Wielgus, Artur, "Homeida," typescript (copy), undated (Box 205, Folder 3168)
    - WNET, "The Second Revolution: Communism in Crisis" (proposal for a television series), typescript, 1989 (Box 205, Folder 3169)
    - Wnętrzak, Rudolf, poems in Polish, typescript, undated (Box 205, Folder 3170)
    - Wojciechowski, Marcin, poems in Polish, typescript, 1986 (Box 205, Folder 3171)
    - Wołkomińska, Felicja, testimony on the Holocaust, typescript (copy), 1986 (Box 205, Folder 3172)
      Includes a letter from the Yad Vashem Archive to Miłosz.
    - Wyszomirski, Michał, various writings in Polish, typescript (copy), 1992 (Box 205, Folder 3173)
    - Zagajewski, Adam
      - Poems, English translation by an unidentified translator, typescript (copy), undated (Box 205, Folder 3174)
      - Poems, English translation by Renata Gorczyńska, drafts, typescript (copy), corrected by Miłosz, 1988 (Box 205, Folder 3175)
    - Zaleśny, Jarek, prose in Polish, typescript, undated (Box 205, Folder 3176)
    - Ziemlański, Włodzimierz, "Polesie i Witkacy," typescript, 1981 (Box 205, Folder 3177)
    - Zlatkes, Gwido (translator), English translations of writings of Aleksander Wat, printout (copy), undated (Box 205, Folder 3178)
    - Żuławski, Andrzej, Moliwda, typescript (copy), 1979 (Box 205, Folder 3179-3181)
    - Various authors, poems dedicated to Josif Stalin, typescript, 1939-1984 (Box 206, Folder 3182)
      By Konstanty Gałczyński, Stanisław Jerzy Lec, Włodzimierz Słobodnik, Elżbieta Szemplińska, Anatol Mikułko, Marian Ośniałowski and Teodor Bujnicki.
    - Various authors, poetry in Polish, printout (copy), undated (Box 206, Folder 3183)
      Includes poems by Miłosz, Stanisław Barańczak and Wiktor Woroszylski.
    - Various authors, poems collected by Miłosz, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 206, Folder 3184)
    - Unidentified prose in Polish, typescripts (copies), undated (Box 206, Folder 3185)
    - Unidentified poems sent to Miłosz, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 206, Folder 3186)
- Printed Material, 1929-1999; Series IX; 11.47; (30 boxes)
  Series IX is organized into five subseries: Writings of Czeslaw Milosz, Clandestine and Samizdat Publications, Clippings and Offprints, Ephemera, and Photocopies of Articles.
  Series IX consists of printed material collected by Miłosz. Writings of Czeslaw Milosz includes clippings from newspapers and journals and individual printed broadsides. Clandestine and samizdat publications include periodicals, collections of poetry and other samizdat publications that were printed outside of the Polish censor's control during the years 1978-1989. The collection, though relatively small, is representative of clandestine publication in Poland during that time. The material documents political, literary and intellectual life under martial law in Poland and the rise of the Solidarity (Solidarność) movement. Clippings and offprints are chiefly about Miłosz and consist of newspaper and magazine articles about his travels, lectures, awards and publications. Ephemera includes announcements for Miłosz's poetry readings, lectures and other events. Photocopies of articles are chiefly on topics related to Polish Literature. Most general clippings are about Czesław Miłosz and include newspaper profiles, interviews and reviews.
  - Writings of Czesław Miłosz
    Photocopies of articles by Miłosz are also filed in the subseries Photocopies of Articles.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1933-1981 (Box 207, Folder 3187-3208)
    - 1982-1990, undated, 1982-1997, undated (Box 208, Folder 3209-3219)
  - Clandestine and Samizdat Publications
    Clandestine and Samizdat Publications is organized under three headings: Serials, Monographs and Fragments. Periodicals are arranged alphabetically by title and monographs are arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Serials
      - Arka (copy), 1985 (Box 209, Folder 3220)
      - Biuletyn POP PZPR, 1980 (Box 209, Folder 3221)
      - Bratniak, 1981 (Box 209, Folder 3222)
      - Czas kultury (copy), 1985 (Box 209, Folder 3223)
      - Dialogi (copies), 1987-1988 (Box 209, Folder 3224)
      - Dziś dla jutra, 1981 (Box 209, Folder 3225)
      - Gazeta Podlaska (copies), 1987 (Box 209, Folder 3226)
      - Informator, 1980-1981 (Box 209, Folder 3227)
      - Kontakt, 1982-1984 (Box 209, Folder 3228)
      - KOS (Komitet Oporu Społecznego) (copies), 1984-1987 (Box 209, Folder 3229-3230)
      - Kultura Niezależna, 1984-1985 (Box 209, Folder 3231)
      - Lithuania, 1981-1984 (Box 209, Folder 3232)
      - Mała Polska, 1985 (Box 210, Folder 3233)
      - Nasz Głos (copy), 1987 (Box 210, Folder 3234)
      - Niepodległość (copy), 1983 (Box 210, Folder 3235)
      - Niezależne słowo, 1981 (Box 210, Folder 3236)
      - Nurt (copy), 1987 (Box 210, Folder 3237)
      - Obecność, 1986 (Box 210, Folder 3238)
      - Okienko niezależne (copy), 1987 (Box 210, Folder 3239)
      - Polityka polska (copy), 1984 (Box 210, Folder 3240)
      - Przegląd wiadomości agencyjnych (copy), 1985 (Box 210, Folder 3241)
      - Przegłos, 1989 (Box 210, Folder 3242)
      - Rezonans, 1981 (Box 210, Folder 3243)
      - Serwis informacyjny, 1981 (Box 210, Folder 3244)
      - Solidarność (various newsletters), 1980-1985 (Box 210, Folder 3245-3248)
      - Spotkania, 1979 (Box 210, Folder 3249)
      - Sprzeciw, 1983 (Box 211, Folder 3250)
      - Tu i teraz, 1983-1985 (Box 211, Folder 3251)
      - Tygodnik Mazowsze, 1985-1986 (Box 211, Folder 3252)
      - Wiadomości dnia, 1980-1981 (Box 211, Folder 3253-3254)
      - Zapis, 1980-1981 (Box 211, Folder 3255-3256)
      - Zeszyty Edukacji Narodowej, 1984 (Box 211, Folder 3257)
    - Monographs
      - Aron, Raymond, Isaiah Berlin and Hannah Arendt, Trójgłos o wolności, 1987 (Box 211, Folder 3258)
      - Ficowski, Jerzy, Gryps (copy), undated (Box 211, Folder 3259)
      - Kowalski, Wiktor, Dziennik z obozów dla internowanych, 1987 (Box 211, Folder 3260)
      - Moczulski, Leszek, Rewolucja bez rewolucji, undated (Box 211, Folder 3261)
      - Próchniak, Paweł, Wiersze, undated (Box 211, Folder 3262)
      - Sadunaite, Nijolé, Promień w ciemnościach, undated (Box 211, Folder 3263)
      - Spis, Michał, Trzeba głosno mówić, 1989 (Box 211, Folder 3264)
      - Wierzbicki, Piotr, Myśli staroświeckiego polaka, 1985 (Box 212, Folder 3265)
      - Zimand, Roman, Miłosz, Tyrmand, Zinowiew, 1985 (Box 212, Folder 3266)
      - Zorkrot, Aleksander, Poryw, 1980 (Box 212, Folder 3267)
      - Various authors, Wilno (copy), undated (Box 212, Folder 3268)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 212, Folder 3269)
  - Clippings and Offprints
    - General Clippings, 1944-1957 (Box 213, Folder 3270-3285)
    - General Clippings, 1957-1962 (Box 214, Folder 3286-3297)
    - General Clippings, 1962-1980 (Box 215, Folder 3298-3319)
    - General Clippings, 1980 (Box 216, Folder 3320-3327)
    - General Clippings, 1980 (Box 217, Folder 3328-3336)
    - General Clippings, 1981 (Box 218, Folder 3337-3345)
    - General Clippings, 1981 (Box 219, Folder 3346-3355)
    - General Clippings, 1981-1983 (Box 220, Folder 3356-3365)
    - General Clippings, 1984-1987 (Box 221, Folder 3366-3376)
    - General Clippings, 1987-1999, undated (Box 222, Folder 3377-3389)
  - Ephemera
    - General ephemera, 1933-1985 (Box 223, Folder 3390-3406)
    - General ephemera, 1986-1999, undated (Box 224, Folder 3407-3418)
    - Posters, 1980-1987, undated (Box bsd, Folder 3419-3420)
  - Photocopies of Articles
    Organized under headings by language.
    - Polish
      - Articles by Czesław Miłosz, undated (Box 225, Folder 3421-3423)
      - Articles about Czesław Miłosz, undated (Box 225, Folder 3424-3427)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 226, Folder 3428-3441)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 227, Folder 3442-3453)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box 228, Folder 3454-3460)
    - English